export const AGRICULTURALSCIENCEA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The gradual exposure of seedlings ready form transplanting to environmental stress is referred as",
A: "blanching",
B: "earthening-up",
C: "hardening-off",
D: "pricking out",
answer: "C. Hardening-off",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The mouldboard plough is used in",
A: "breaking hard pans",
B: "breaking soil clods completely",
C: "completely inverting the soil",
D: "removing tree stumps",
answer: "C. Completely inverting the soil",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The hormone responsible for milk let down in sows is",
A: "adrenaline",
B: "progesterone",
C: "oestrogen",
D: "oxytocin",
answer: "D. Oxytocin",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A feed ingredient that has been ground and moistened to a near paste state is described as",
A: "bran",
B: "cake",
C: "mash",
D: "meal",
answer: "C. Mash",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following effects of disease on crops are correct?  \nI. Increase in cost of production  \nII. Increase in photosynthetic ability  \nIII. Reduction in the quality of produce",
A: "I and II only",
B: "l and Ill only",
C: "II and Ill only",
D: "I, II and Ill",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The machine used for removing seeds from the maize cob is referred to as",
A: "decorticator",
B: "dehusker",
C: "hammer mill",
D: "sheller",
answer: "D. Sheller",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The reasons for packaging agricultural produce include:  \nI. Ease of handling  \nII. Increase shelf life  \nIII. Elimination of Brokerage",
A: "I and II only",
B: "l and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A brooder room should have an initial 4-week temperature range of",
A: "14 °C to 30 °C",
B: "20 °C to 31 °C",
C: "21 °C to 35 °C",
D: "35 °C to 50 °C",
answer: "C. 21 °C to 35 °C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Maintenance of fish pond after harvesting does not include",
A: "agitating the soil at the bottom of the pond and liming it",
B: "putting outlet and inlet screens in place",
C: "removing the silt and mending cracks in walls",
D: "cleaning the inlet and outlet pipes or gutters and screens",
answer: "B. Putting outlet and inlet screens in place",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Price fluctuation of agricultural produce can be controlled by",
A: "adequate storage facilities",
B: "good agronomic practices",
C: "good extension services",
D: "production of high quality produce",
answer: "A. Adequate storage facilities",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following practices is least effective in reducing soil erosion?",
A: "Earthening-up",
B: "Plastic mulching",
C: "Cover cropping",
D: "Fertilizer application",
answer: "D. Fertilizer application",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The function of the crank shaft of a tractor engines is to",
A: "control the opening and dosing of the valves",
B: "convert vertical motion into rotational motion",
C: "keep the engine turning during idle strokes",
D: "mix fuel and air for combustion",
answer: "B. Convert vertical motion into rotational motion",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The recommended seed rate for a maize variety is 20kg/ha. Determine the amount of seed required for a 1 .8 ha farm land.",
A: "11.1 kg",
B: "21.8 kg",
C: "26.0 kg",
D: "36.0 kg",
answer: "C. 26.0 kg",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Farmers in West Africa often find it difficult to obtain loans from the bank for agricultural project because they",
A: "have no guarantor",
B: "have no collateral",
C: "have no tac clearance certificates",
D: "lack technical know how",
answer: "B. Have no collateral",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. In the male reproductive system of farm animals, sperm maturation and storage is the function of",
A: "epididymis",
B: "penis",
C: "urethra",
D: "vas deferens",
answer: "A. Epididymis",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. One of the main disadvantages of mechanical tilage is the",
A: "high initial cost of equipment",
B: "need for special training before machines could be use",
C: "use of heavy equipment leading to soil compaction",
D: "use of foreign exchange to purchase machine parts",
answer: "C. Use of heavy equipment leading to soil compaction",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Determine the plant population per hectare of a farmland if the planting distance is of cabbage is 75 cm by 60 cm",
A: "2,222",
B: "20,800",
C: "26,400",
D: "37,800",
answer: "B. 20,800",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following roles are played by non-governmental organizations in the development of Agriculture in West Africa?  \nI. Helps fanners to obtain credit  \nII. Provides land for farmers  \nIII. Transfers agricultural technology to farmers",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and Ill only",
C: "II and Ill only",
D: "I, II and Ill",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The control of tsetseflies minimizes the spread of",
A: "aspergillosis",
B: "coccidiosis",
C: "trypanosomiasis",
D: "tuberculosis",
answer: "C. Trypanosomiasis",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The primary function of the piston in an internal combustion engine is to",
A: "ignite the compressed air",
B: "inject fuel into the hot air",
C: "enable inlet valve open",
D: "compress fuel-air mixture",
answer: "D. Compress fuel-air mixture",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Determine the average output of maize when four bags of fertilizer are use",
A: "5.0",
B: "6.9",
C: "7.0",
D: "8.0",
answer: "C. 7.0",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The marginal product between 6.0 and 7.0 bags of fertilizer is",
A: "0.0",
B: "1.0",
C: "2.0",
D: "3.0",
answer: "B. 1.0",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. *******************************",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which of the following breeds of fowls are dual purpose?  \nI. Light Sussex and Rhode Island Red  \nII. Dark Comish and Minorca  \nIII. White Leghorn and White Plymouth rock",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and Ill only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The opening and closing of the valves of the tractor engine is controlled by the",
A: "cram shaft",
B: "connecting rod",
C: "crankshaft",
D: "spark plugs",
answer: "A. Cram shaft",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The market agent whose role is only to bring buyers and sellers together is known as",
A: "a retailer",
B: "an itinerant trader",
C: "a commissioned trader",
D: "a broker",
answer: "D. A broker",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Which of the following parts can be found on a mouldboard plough",
A: "Disc",
B: "Furrow wheel",
C: "Share",
D: "Spring time",
answer: "C. Share",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Which of the following statements about colostrum are correct? I. Colostrum has more nutrients than ordinary milk. II. Colostrum acts as a laxative. Ill. Colostrum provides more immunity for young animals.",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and llI only",
C: "II and Ill only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II, and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The spacing of maize is 90 cm by 30 cm and there are two pants per stand. Determine the population of maize plants on a hectare farmland.",
A: "27,000",
B: "37,037",
C: "54,000",
D: "74,074",
answer: "C. 54,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following rocks are sedimentary?  \nI. Granite\nII. Limestone \nIII. Shale",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "C. II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following nutrients causes Blossom-end-rot in tomato when deficient in the soil?",
A: "Calcium",
B: "Magnesium",
C: "Sulphur",
D: "iron",
answer: "A. Calcium",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The rapid decline in soil fertility in West African soils is mainly due to",
A: "application of inorganic fertilizers",
B: "overgrazing",
C: "continuous mechanization",
D: "bush burning",
answer: "D. Bush burning",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The removal of excess water from the soil is known as",
A: "evaporation",
B: "drainage",
C: "percolation",
D: "transpiration",
answer: "B. Drainage",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Maintenance activities in a fish pond include",
A: "manuring of the pond",
B: "mending of cracks in pond walls",
C: "regular harvesting of fish",
D: "timely feeding of fish",
answer: "B. Mending of cracks in pond walls",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The zone of illuviation in a soil profile is found in the",
A: "horizon A",
B: "horizon B",
C: "horizon C",
D: "horizon D",
answer: "B. Horizon B",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following ways do grasses help control soil erosion?  \nI. Binding soil particles together  \nII. Reducing impact of rain drops  \nIII. preventing water from percolating through the soil",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and lll only",
C: "II and Ill only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The causal organism of maize rust disease is",
A: "bacteriumB.",
B: "fungus",
C: "nematode",
D: "virus",
answer: "B. Fungus",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following fish preservation methods is commonly used in West Africa?",
A: "Canning",
B: "Irradiation",
C: "Freezing",
D: "Smoking",
answer: "D. Smoking",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The process of separating agricultural produce into uniform lots is referred to as",
A: "sorting",
B: "standardization",
C: "storage",
D: "packaging",
answer: "B. Standardization",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The male inflorescence of a maize plant is the",
A: "cob",
B: "ear",
C: "tassel",
D: "silk",
answer: "C. Tassel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following factors does not affect soil formation?  \nI. Climate  \nII. Time  \nlll. Topography",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and Ill only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "D. I, II, and III",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Knowledge of soil profile is important in agriculture because",
A: "soil scientists use it to formulate inorganic fertilizers",
B: "it promotes the weathering of rocks",
C: "it determines the soil catena",
D: "it gives indication of the type of crops to grow",
answer: "D. It gives an indication of the type of crops to grow",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. An example of a farming system that protects the environment is",
A: "ecological farming",
B: "mixed farming",
C: "ley farming",
D: "pastoral farming",
answer: "A. Ecological farming",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following farming practices could reduce excessive evaporation of water?",
A: "Harrowing",
B: "Liming",
C: "Mulching",
D: "Ploughing",
answer: "C. Mulching",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Taungya farming involves the combination of",
A: "crop husbandry and animal husbandry",
B: "crop husbandry and fish farming",
C: "crop husbandry and forestry",
D: "forestry and animal husbandry",
answer: "C. Crop husbandry and forestry",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The most important factor limiting agricultural mechanization in West Africa is",
A: "inadequate storage facilities",
B: "lack of technical know-how",
C: "poor marketing systems",
D: "small land holding",
answer: "D. Small land holding",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The stomach compartment from which food is regurgitated directly into the mouth of ruminant is the",
A: "abomasum",
B: "omasum",
C: "reticulum",
D: "rumen",
answer: "D. Rumen",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following factors are considered in selecting species for alley cropping?  \nI. Excellent coppicing ability  \nII. Ability to fix atmospheric nitrogen  \nIII. Shallow rooting system",
A: "l and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "II and III only",
D: "I, II and III",
answer: "A. I and II only",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. A major disadvantage of monoculture is that",
A: "farm cannot be mechanized",
B: "soil texture is destroyed",
C: "soil nutrients are leached",
D: "diseases and pests spread easily",
answer: "D. Diseases and pests spread easily",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The main problem of pastoral farming in West Africa is",
A: "destruction of crops on farm lands",
B: "high incidence of trypanosomiasis",
C: "unavailability of settlement for herdsmen",
D: "unlimited natural pasture for animals",
answer: "A. Destruction of crops on farmlands",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},


]